(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
あっ...
Ah...
What can I do for you?
I can hear you
What can I do for you, baby?
What can I do for you?
real Emotion
Lyrics: Kenn Kato Music: 原 一博
Lyrics: Kenn Kato Music: Kazuhiro Hara
あの日ココロの彼方に
Beyond the heart of that day
描いてた場所にいる
I am in the place I pictured
途方に暮れてたりする
Sometimes I'm at a loss
けれどももう戻れない
But I can't go back anymore
夢に見たカタチとは
From the shape I saw in my dreams
なにもかもが違う
Everything is different
現実には
In reality
眩暈さえする
It even makes me dizzy
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情
Emotions swaying in the real world
負けたくない
I don't want to lose
もうただ走るしかないこの胸に
In this chest that has no choice but to run
聴こえてくる
I can hear it
越えてキミは一人じゃない
Surpassing it, you are not alone
What can I do for you?
I CAN HEAR YOU
決して振り向きはしない
I'll never look back
あなたには頼らない
I won't depend on you
なにかがあれば必ず
If anything happens, surely
すぐに来てくれるから
You'll come right away
いまぼくにできること
What I can do now
それは信じること...
Is to believe...
真実なら
If it's the truth
この胸にある
It's in my heart
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情
Emotions swaying in the real world
支えるのはそうあなたが
Supported by, yes, you
教えてくれたすべて
Everything you taught me
いまの私だから、
Because it's who I am now,
だから、一人じゃない
So, I'm not alone
What can I do for you?
What can I do
I CAN HEAR YOU
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情
Emotions swaying in the real world
感じてもあなたが
Even if I feel them, you
目を閉じたらそこにいる
Are there when I close my eyes
絆がある
There's a bond
だから、一人じゃない
So, I'm not alone
リアルな世界に揺れてる感情
Emotions swaying in the real world
負けたくない
I don't want to lose
もうただ走るしかないこの胸に
In my heart that now just has to run
聞こえてくる
I can hear it
キミは一人じゃない
You are not alone
What can I do for you?
I CAN HEAR YOU
オドループ
Lyrics, Music: Koji Mihara
Oddloop
踊ってるだけで退場
Leaving just for dancing
それをそっかそっかって言って
Saying "I see, I see" to that
お幸せについて問う
Questioning about happiness
何が正義なんかって思う
Thinking about what justice is
生意気そうにガム噛んで
Chewing gum insolently
それもいいないいなって思う
Thinking that's nice too
テレスコープ越しの感情
Emotions through a telescope
どこかに全部詰め込んだ
Crammed them all somewhere
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
I don't like a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
I don't like a night without dancing
気に入らない夜なんて僕は知らない
I don't know any nights I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて
A night without a night without dancing is
とってもとっても退屈です
Very, very boring
想ってるだけで行動
Just thinking and acting
きっとないと音楽も踊る
Even the music dances, surely
ダンスでダンスする現状
Dancing a dance, current state
これはチャンスなんかって思う
Thinking maybe this is a chance
カセットがほらタンタン
Look, the cassette goes tan-tan
タタタンタンタタタンタン
Ta-ta-tan-tan, ta-ta-tan-tan
踊ってない夜を知らない人とか
Those who don't know a night without dancing
この世に一人もございません
There's not a single one in this world
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
I don't like a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
I don't like a night without dancing
気に入らない夜なんて僕は知らない
I don't know any nights I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて
A night without a night without dancing is
とってもとっても退屈です
Very, very boring
いつも待ってる
Always waiting
ダンスホールは待ってる
The dance hall is waiting
変わってく変わってく
Changing, changing
傷だらけでも待つ
Waiting even if covered in wounds
ほら 踊ってる
See, I'm dancing
ダンスホールの未来に
In the dance hall's future
色を塗っていくのは あなた あなた
The one painting the colors is you, you
ダンスは笑顔で待ってる
The dance is waiting with a smile
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
I don't like a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
I don't like a night without dancing
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't know any more nights I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて
A night without a night without dancing
踊ってたい夜を知りたい
I want to know a night where I want to dance
踊ってたい夜を気に入りた〜い
I want to like a night where I want to dance
踊ってない夜を知らない
I don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
I don't like a night without dancing
気に入らない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't know any more nights I don't like
踊ってない夜がない夜なんて
A night without a night without dancing
とってもとってもとっても大切なんです
It's very, very, very important
とってもとってもとっても大切です
HiRyS, it's IRyS from hololive English -Promise-
hololive EnglishのIRySです！
I'm IRyS from hololive English!
Welcome to my birthday live, Hope Upon a Star!
Thank you so, so much for coming!
今年の誕生日ライブ見に来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to see this year's birthday live!
Hope Upon a Star、今年はちょっと誕生日よりちょっとだけ遅いんですけど、誕生日ライブです！
Hope Upon a Star, it's a bit later than my birthday this year, but it's my birthday live!
Yes, it's a little bit later than my actual birthday, but, you know, it's no problem.
Please do post your comments and screenshots using the hashtag...
...#IRySBDay2025 written over here!
I'd be really happy if you took a lot of screenshots, 'cause there's gonna be a lot of cool moments. Yay!
今回のライブのハッシュタグは #IRySBDay2025 です！
The hashtag for this live is #IRySBDay2025!
ぜひ感想とかスクショもたくさん撮ってポストしてくれたら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots and post your thoughts!
じゃあね、ちょっとみんなに見せたいものがあるんだ！
Now then, I have something I want to show everyone!
I have something I really want to show you guys.
So let me go prepare real quick!
ジャン！
Ta-da!
It's the 6th Fes outfit! It's the Bright...
Was that the title? The... the...
...the Colorize outfit!
It's so cute, right? I love this outfit so much.
今年の6th Fes衣装、早速着てみました！
I tried on this year's 6th Fes outfit right away!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いでしょ？ もう最高、最高！
Isn't it super cute? It's just the best!
I love this outfit so much, it's just so pretty, it's elegant, it's so pretty and it looks so... yeah!
What do you guys think? Do you guys think it's cute? Yeah, very cute.
Anyways, the concept of this live concert is to sing my favorite songs from different eras of music...
...focusing on dance and some Euro, 'cause I know you guys love Euro as much as I do, right? Yeah!
There are also different kinds of music players for each song all over this stage. Can you spot them all?
今回のライブは、アイリスの好きなダンス曲やユーロビートの曲を懐かしい曲から新しい曲まで...
This live features IRyS's favorite dance and Eurobeat tracks, from classics to new hits...
...いろんな楽曲デバイスと一緒に歌いまくります！ みんな楽しんでってね！
...singing along with various music devices! Hope you all enjoy!
Speaking of which, talking about music devices, what do you guys think of my jukebox?
Isn't it big and cool? Yeah!
I put a lot of songs in here, so how about we start the next song? Yeah!
このジュークボックスかっこよくない？ たくさんの曲が入ってるんだ。
Isn't this jukebox cool? It has lots of songs in it.
じゃあ早速、次の曲いってみようかな？
Well then, shall we head into the next song?
この後もね、ゲスト曲はたくさんあり、
There are many guest songs after this,
なんと最後の方に重大発表もありますんで、
and there will also be a major announcement towards the end,
最後まで一緒に楽しんで盛り上げていきましょう！
so let's enjoy and heat things up together until the very end!
Please stay tuned as we have a lot of guest songs coming up
and I have a big, big, big announcement to share with y'all as well.
So excited, so make sure you watch it until the end.
Yeah!
Please listen to ROCKIN' HARDCORE.
ROCKIN' HARDCORE
Lyrics: E.SOMENZI Music: Stefano Castagna, Christian Codenotti
Go man go rocking over the globe
Everybody go
Everybody ride
Sparking glow baby squeeze out your soul
Till you're reaching high
Devil in the sky
Fun fun baby
Feel all the power, feel all the fire
Moving crazy
Shake it to the beat of the night
Rocking hardcore over the world
Stomp your feet back to the ground
Rocking hardcore losing control
Oh baby rock just for you
Rocking hardcore let yourself go
Move it honey one more time
Rocking hardcore losing control
I'm feeling hot feeling good
Round the round never chasing you down
Baby that's so high freedom is inside
Devil's son yes I know I'm the one
Never acting wise got no reason why
Fun fun baby
Feel all the power, feel all the fire
Moving crazy
Shake it to the beat of the night
Rocking hardcore over the world
Stomp your feet back to the ground
Rocking hardcore losing control
Oh baby rock just for you
Rocking hardcore let yourself go
Move it honey one more time
Rocking hardcore losing control
I'm feeling hot feeling good
Rocking hardcore over the world
Go man go rocking over the globe
Sparking glow baby squeeze out your soul
Devil in the sky
Fun fun baby
Feel all the power, feel all the fire
Moving crazy
Shake it to the beat of the night
Rocking hardcore over the world
Stomp your feet back to the ground
Rocking hardcore losing control
Oh baby rock just for you
Rocking hardcore let yourself go
Move it honey one more time
Rocking hardcore losing control
I'm feeling hot feeling good
LEVEL5 -judgelight-
Lyrics: fripSide Music: 八木沼 悟志
Lyrics: fripSide Music: Satoshi Yaginuma
響きあう 願いが今 覚醒めてく
The resonating wishes are awakening now
譲れない 未来のために
For the sake of a future I won't give up on
巡りあう 運命を 越えたその先に
Beyond the destiny we've encountered
この想い 輝くから
Because these feelings will shine
強さの本当の意味をさ
The true meaning of strength,
捜し続けてた
I kept searching for it
ありのままの痛みを
Accepting pain
受け入れるその意味を
just as it is
明日へ走り続ける
I learned from you
君に知った
running toward tomorrow
巡りゆく景色が今
The rotating scenery
流れてく 手繰り寄せた世界の先
is flowing now, beyond the world I've drawn close
降り注ぐシグナルを身体で感じて
Feeling the pouring signals with my body,
解き放つ今全てを
I release everything now
Just truth in my heart いつだって迷わないよ
Just truth in my heart, I won't ever hesitate
消せない想いがあるから
because I have feelings that can't be erased
解き明かす真実から瞳を逸らさずに
Without turning my eyes away from the truth I've solved,
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
遠く感じてた
I felt it was far away,
君が走る背中を
the back of you running
いつからだろう
Since when was it,
こんなにも近くに感じる
I feel you so close
不安隠し切れずに
Unable to hide my anxiety,
迫る空を見上げた
I looked up at the approaching sky
傷ついた記憶
The wounded memories,
いつか乗り越えるよ
I will overcome them someday
憧れは能力を今呼び起こす
Yearning now awakens my ability
守りたいものがあるから
because there is something I want to protect
巡りゆく景色胸に駆け上がるだけ
Just running up with the rotating scenery in my heart,
痛みは風に消えてく
the pain disappears into the wind
Believe in judgelight 運命さえ撃ち抜いて
Believe in judgelight, even shooting through fate,
夜明けをこの手で造ろう
let's create the dawn with these hands
変えていく勇気と変わらない心で
With the courage to change and an unchanging heart,
I believe myself and precious emotion
打ち砕くこの想いで！
With these feelings that crush!
始まりの光の中誓い合う
Vowing to each other in the light of the beginning,
果てなき闇を裁くこと
to judge the endless darkness
恐れてた孤独の渦溺れることに
I was afraid of drowning in a whirlpool of loneliness
だけどもう振り向かない
but I won't look back anymore
巡りゆく景色が今流れてく
The rotating scenery is flowing now,
手繰り寄せた世界の先
beyond the world I've drawn close
降り注ぐシグナルを身体で感じて
Feeling the pouring signals with my body,
解き放つ今全てを
I release everything now
Just truth in my heart いつだって迷わないよ
Just truth in my heart, I won't ever hesitate
消せない想いがあるから
because I have feelings that can't be erased
解き明かす真実から瞳を逸らさずに
Without turning my eyes away from the truth I've solved,
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
確かな絆信じて
Believing in our certain bond
ワンルーム・ディスコ ディスコ
One Room Disco, Disco,
One Room Disco, Disco
ディスコ ディスコ ワンルーム・ディスコ
Disco, Disco, One Room Disco,
ディスコ ディスコ
Disco, Disco
なんだって少なめ
Everything is sparse,
半分の生活
a life of halves
だけど荷物は重い
But my luggage is heavy,
気分は軽い
my mood is light
窓を開けても
Even if I open the window,
見慣れない風景
it's an unfamiliar landscape
ちょっと落ち着かないけれど
I'm a bit restless, but
そのうち楽しくなるでしょう
I'll probably start having fun soon
新しい場所で
I wonder if I can do well
上手くやっていけるかな
in this new place
部屋を片付けて
Cleaning up the room
買い物に出かけよう
Let's go out shopping
遠い空の向こう
Beyond the distant sky
君は何を思うの
What are you thinking?
飛ぶ　できるはずって
To fly, thinking that I can do it
思わなきゃしょうがない
I have to believe it
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
なんたって少なめ
After all, it's quite small
半分の生活
This half-sized life
だけど気になるカロリー
But I'm worried about calories
気分は軽い
I'm feeling light
シャンプーをしながら
While I'm shampooing
目を閉じたまま
With my eyes closed
シャワーも出せないけれど
I can't even get the shower to work
そのうち慣れてくるでしょう
But I'll get used to it soon
新しい場所で
In this new place
うまくやっていけるかな
I wonder if I can do well
音楽をかけて
I'll put some music on
計画をねりねり
And think up some plans
今日はなんだかね
For some reason today
おもしろいこともないし
Nothing interesting is happening
リズムにゆられたいんだ
I just want to sway to the rhythm
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
昼間みたい
Just like daytime
街の灯りが
The city lights
星空を
Make the starry sky
見えなくする
Impossible to see
たくさんの
So many
まぶしい光
Dazzling lights
溶けて消えちゃいそうだ
It feels like they'll melt and vanish
新しい場所で
In this new place
うまくやっていけるかな
I wonder if I can do well
部屋を片付けて
I'll tidy up my room
買い物に出かけよう
And go out shopping
遠い空の向こう
Beyond the distant sky
君は何を思うの
What are you thinking?
飛ぶ　できるはずって
To fly, thinking that I can do it
思わなきゃしょうがない
I have to believe it
新しい場所で
In this new place
うまくやっていけるかな
I wonder if I can do well
音楽をかけて
I'll put some music on
計画をねりねり
And think up some plans
今日はなんだかね
For some reason today
おもしろいこともないし
Nothing interesting is happening
リズムにゆられたいんだ
I just want to sway to the rhythm
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
ワンルーム・ディスコ
One-room disco
ディスコ　ディスコ
Disco, disco
微笑みの爆弾
Lyrics: リーシャウロン Music: 馬渡 松子
Smile Bomb
Lyrics: Li Shoron Music: Matsuko Mawatari
街の人ごみが　ぶつかってひとりぼっち
The city crowds bump into me, and I'm all alone
果てない砂漠を　びゅうんとひとりぼっち
Speeding through the endless desert, I'm all alone
どっちだろう
Which one is it?
泣きたくなる場所は
The place that makes me want to cry
2重丸をつけて
Drawing a double circle
ちょっぴり
Just a little
オトナさ
Adulthood
メチャメチャ 苦しい壁だってふいに
A sudden, impossibly difficult wall
なぜか ぶち壊す 勇気とPOWER 湧いてくるのは
Somehow, the courage and POWER to smash it comes welling up
メチャメチャ 厳しい人達がふいに
The people who are incredibly strict suddenly
見せた 優しさの せいだったり するんだろうね
Showed kindness, and that must be the reason
アリガトウゴザイます!
Thank you very much!
今まで 何回 よろしくと元気に 叫んだだろう
I wonder how many times I've energetically shouted 'Hello!'
今まで 何回 さよならと泣いて 別れただろう
I wonder how many times I've cried while saying 'Goodbye'
どっちだろう 比べて多い 数は
I wonder which one has the higher count
中にイコール 書いて
Drawing an equals sign in the middle
ちょっぴりオトナさ
I'm a little bit of an adult
メチャメチャ 悲しいときだってふいに
Even when I'm incredibly sad, suddenly
なぜか 乗り越える 勇気とPOWER 湧いてくるのは
Somehow, the courage and POWER to overcome it comes welling up
メチャメチャ やさしい人達がふいに
The people who are incredibly kind suddenly
見せた 厳しさの せいだったり するんだろうね
Showed strictness, and that must be the reason
アリガトウゴザイます!
Thank you very much!
メチャメチャ 苦しい壁だってふいに
A sudden, impossibly difficult wall
なぜか ぶち壊す 勇気とPOWER 湧いてくるのは
Somehow, the courage and POWER to smash it comes welling up
メチャメチャ 厳しい人達がふいに
The people who are incredibly strict suddenly
見せた 優しさの せいだったり するんだろうね
Showed kindness, and that must be the reason
メチャメチャ 楽しいときだって 忘れないよ
I won't forget even the incredibly fun times
いつまでも 勇気とPOWER なくさないよ
I'll never lose my courage and POWER
メチャメチャ ひとりぼっちの人に あげる
I'll give it to the people who are incredibly lonely
唇の 裏側に 隠してある
Hidden on the inside of my lips
微笑みの爆弾!
The Smile Bomb!
And that was Hohoemi no Bakudan!
Osh! Osh! Osh! Osh!
Why is it not turning off?
You guys didn't hear anything, right?
何も聞いてないよね？
You guys were deaf for a second, I'm sure, right?
何も聞いてない。大丈夫。
You didn't hear anything. It's fine.
Anyways, do you guys know what this is?
It's my boombox!
ラジカセでございます。
It is a radio cassette player.
I'll be using this later, so let me put it back down.
But I just wanted to do that. It's my boombox.
It changes the world, but I don't have boiled goose.
Anyways, it's cool and retro, and actually...
I have a couple of announcements for the show.
But first, I want to talk about one obvious announcement.
The merch!
Yes! 実は今回のライブは...
Yes! Actually, for this live...
ビッグなお知らせが本当にたくさんあるんですけど...
there are really a lot of big announcements...
その前にね、IRySの記念グッズ、紹介しようと思います。
but before that, I'd like to introduce IRyS's commemorative goods.
Isn't it cute? I wanted to create a set that matches the retro feel of today's live.
So let's take a look at what kind of goods are available.
ではどんなグッズがあるのか、見ていきましょう！
Then let's see what kind of goods there are!
First off, we have the Concert PosteRyS!
Isn't it sexy?
I wanted to make it look like a poster for an in-real-life concert.
This time, actually, continuing from last time as well...
the illustration is by Pisuke-sensei!
Say, I love P-suke-sensei's art.
She has an amazing fashion sense.
The outfits are always so peak.
Just look at this sexy disco-style outfit.
Yes, it's sexy, right? Yes, it's sexy.
えーとね、まずは最初はこちら、コンサートポスタリスでございます。
First off, here is the Concert PosteRyS.
リアルライブのグッズとかで見たことあるかな？大きなポスターです。
Have you seen this kind of thing as real live merch? It's a big poster.
それをね、アイリスも作ってみたくて、今回P-suke先生に素敵な絵を描いてもらって、作っていただきました。
I wanted to make one too, so I had P-suke-sensei draw a wonderful illustration for it.
みんなどうかな？かわいいよね。
What do you all think? It's cute, right?
And next...
We have the Concert T-ShirtRyS.
It's my first time releasing a T-shirt, if we don't count the Omacat ones.
You need to have a T-shirt for a live concert, of course, right?
I know we're not at an in-person venue,
but I hope you buy a shirt as a memento of this 3D live and you can wear it for future stuff, future events, yeah!
今回の3Dライブの思い出に買ってもらえると嬉しいです。
I hope you'll buy it as a memory of this 3D live.
And we still have more!
The third item is the BackpackRyS.
I love the little details in the design, like the zipper charm and the lining.
Yeah, it's like a bigger version of the shoulder bagRyS, which I think a lot of you guys liked.
I put a lot of thought into all of this, and it's perfect for carrying all of your IRyS merch!
ぜひね、イベントやライブなどで使ってね。もうめっちゃかっこいいんで。ぜひぜひぜひ。
Please use it at events and concerts. It's really cool, so definitely check it out.
And finally...
We have the YabaiRyS Keychain!
I know you guys, and me personally, have all been wanting a doll that has this face.
Look at it. She's so cute. I wonder what she's thinking about.
Surely, 'seiso' thoughts. When you press her, she makes a sound.
Surely, a 'seiso' sound. Um, you can put her on your BackpackRyS and take her everywhere with you.
ヤバいことが起きても、ヤバリスが何とかしてくれることないかも...
Even if something bad happens, YabaiRyS might not be able to help...
まあ、この顔なんでね。うん。
Well, look at that face. Yeah.
Anyways, the full set will include the backstage pass style card.
I'll be hand-signing the limited edition set, and the regular set will be foil-stamped, as per usual.
フルセット買っていただくと特典でスタッフパス風カードがついていきまーす。
If you buy the full set, you'll get a staff pass style card as a bonus.
えっと、数量限定版にはアイリスの直筆サイン、通常版のフルセットには箔押し複製サインがつきます。
The limited edition set comes with my handwritten signature, and the regular full set comes with a foil-stamped replica signature.
お間違い無いように。アイリスの汚い字みたいよね。なので、お急ぎ。
Don't mix them up. You want to see my messy handwriting, right? So hurry up.
And that's not all!
Every set will include a special Oshi-holo-men card for the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
You can only get this promo card if you buy the full set.
Yeah, and surely, it's IRyS's card, it must have like absolutely amazing stats.
Yeah, surely, surely. Um, if you haven't played yet, you can check out the card details...
and how to play on the official card game homepage, so be sure to check it out!
さらに、さらに、フルセット特典がもう一つあります。
And there's even more! Another full set bonus.
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚つきます。
You'll get one card that can be used in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME.
フルセットを購入した人だけの特別な推しホロメンカードです。
It's a special Oshi-holo-men card only for those who purchase the full set.
まだ遊んだことない人は、ホームページでカードの詳細や遊び方を、確認できるから、ぜひチェックしてみてね。
If you haven't played yet, you can find card details and instructions on the website, so be sure to check it out!
もうアイリスのカードだから絶対めっちゃ強いと思います。
It's my card, so I'm sure it's incredibly strong.
And that's all for the merch announcements.
Merch sales will open after the main part of the live.
このあとカートオープンだよ！
The cart will open right after this!
I still have another big announcement coming up, so please stay until the end!
I can't wait to share it with you, man.
ライブ後半にも重大告知、発表がまだあります。
There's still a major announcement coming up in the second half of the live.
ライブもまだまだ続くから、最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
The live is still going, so let's keep the energy up until the end!
Yeah, we're already halfway... Oh, the next song is starting.
Okay, I gotta go, I gotta go!
Break it out! Come back at once!
理想、満足してた 少しの希望だけで
I was satisfied with ideals, With just a little bit of hope
待ってれば誰かが未来 決めてくれていた
Someone was deciding the future for me While I waited
Just make it out, come back it once!
なんて小さい自分なんだろう Burst it out!
How small am I? Burst it out!
You know you gotta move it up and break it!
今すぐ夢まで走ろう
Let's run towards our dreams right now
Wake up, make it out, are you lucky time? Hands up!
Rock and roll!
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a rumble!
Gamble Rumble
ギリギリのステージ
On this edge-of-your-seat stage
Gamble you gotta dive into a scramble
1ミリも迷わずに
Without a single millimeter of hesitation
守るべきものなんて 実はそんなにない
There aren't actually that many things worth protecting
Give it up, give it up
少しだけ強がって
Putting on a bit of a brave face
かけましょう全部 play the game
Let's bet it all and play the game
Wake up, wake up, get up, get up
Let's get bubbles to the jumbo
ずっと踏まえよ散歩 絶好上がりっぱなしバンボー
Keep on walking, a top-notch rising combo
東京 無双 22時 皆様の網に
Tokyo peerless at 22:00, in everyone's net
爆音で おまえのうざいとか言われたって Alien
Even if they call you annoying at full blast, you're an alien
I like you moving moving, I make you move it do it
ド派手なバイブスのコマン ギラギラの気持ち持って
Come on with flashy vibes, keep that sparkling feeling
スタートからゴールまで 山ほど舞って 待って
From start to finish, dance and wait a ton
パワーしてマッハゴー レッツゴー 突き刺してコッチへ
Power up, Mach Go, let's go, pierce through this way
Yeah the stage
ぼやっとして自分らしさを
Being vague about your own identity
気づいて過ごしていたい
I want to spend my time noticing it
代償に手に入れたのは 古くさいモラル
What I got in exchange was a stale moral code
臆病なこの胸から 今バステッド
Now, bursting from this cowardly heart
Move it up and break it!
何も持たないで飛び出そう
Let's fly out with nothing in hand
Gamble you gotta chance to make a rumble
研ぎ澄まされていく
Everything is being sharpened
Gamble you gotta dive into a scramble
直感を信じて
Trust your intuition
本命の君の愛以外いらなくて
I don't need anything but your true love
Give it up, give it up
少しでも迷うもの 捨てましょう
Throw away everything that makes you hesitate
It's gonna feel so fine
むらむら飛び出す 突拍子もねえ
Start moving on a whim
不貞腐れずに D.A.J. 人類殺到の芸者
Without sulking, D.A.J., a geisha the world flocks to
オーバーフルボウルもっともっと全部吐き出しちゃおうか
Shall we spit it all out, over full bowl?
Hah Gamble Rumble!
Gamble you gotta chance to make a rumble
溢れだす目眩が
The overflowing dizziness
Gamble you gotta dive into a scramble
ハジケそうなラストゲーム
A last game about to burst
Gamble you gotta chance to make a rumble
ギリギリのステージ
On this edge-of-your-seat stage
Gamble you gotta dive into a scramble
1ミリも迷わずに
Without a single millimeter of hesitation
一瞬の選択で
With a single choice...
すべてをなくしても
...even if I lose everything
Give it up, give it up
後悔は見せないで あかるく負けて泣きましょう
Don't show any regret, let's lose brightly and cry
VALENTI
確実にわたしの
Truly my...
未来を巻き込んで
...future is swept up
恋は走り出した
Love started racing
君の手をつかんだ
I grabbed your hand
両側から燃える
Burning from both sides
花火みたいだった
It was like fireworks
視線もはなせない
I can't take my eyes off you
Oh, Step in Step in, Baby
どうして出逢えたの
Why did we meet?
どうしてわたしなの
Why me?
Boy, I fall in love with you
この瞬間も
Even in this moment...
タイトなジーンズにねじ込む
Squeezing into tight jeans
わたしという戦うBody
My fighting Body
どんなちいさな願いにも
In even the smallest of wishes
貫くチャンスをあげて
Give it the chance to break through
My Dream
破れたジーンズと 繊細すぎる目を 守ってあげたくて
Wanting to protect those torn jeans and those too-sensitive eyes...
ずっとしてあげたくて
...to always be there for you.
家族には言えない
I can't tell my family,
大事なものくらい
but at least my precious things,
自分でも守れるよ
I can protect them myself.
そこを飛び越えてよ
Leap across that boundary.
Oh, step in step in baby
無意味な強がりも
Pointless bravado,
勝手な唇も
and selfish lips.
Just I fall in love with you
全部受け取って
Take it all in.
君と私の間に
If between you and me,
愛が見つけられないなら
love cannot be found,
世界中の中どこにも
then anywhere in the world,
そんなものなんてないの My dream
such a thing doesn't exist. My dream.
Baby I fall in love with you
We can make it last forever
Tell me what you want come to me
Give me all your love
Baby I fall in love with you
We can make it last forever
Tell me what you want come to me
Give me all your love
離れちゃ意味ないじゃん
There's no point if we're apart.
毅然としてたいじゃん
I want to stay resolute.
Boy I fall in love with you (yeah yeah)
ここで戦って
Fight right here.
走る鼓動を選んだ
We chose our racing heartbeats.
二人という生きてるボディ
Two of us, living bodies.
どんな微かな予感にも
For every faint premonition,
信じる力をあげて My dream
give it the strength to believe. My dream.
タイトなジーンズにねじ込む
Squeezing into tight jeans,
私という戦うボディ
the fighting body that is me.
どんな小さな願いにも
For every tiny wish,
輝くチャンスをあげて My dream
give it a chance to shine. My dream.
Fun Fun We hit the step step
揺れる瞳の中
Within these swaying eyes,
We know we love oh
Heat Heat Beat's like a skip skip
ときめきを運ぶよ
Carrying this excitement,
Choo Choo TRAIN
まだ知らない Zone
To a zone still unknown,
目指すよ Tonight
we're aiming for it tonight.
リアルな時が止まる
Real time comes to a stop,
Edge of Time
誰も Cry or Smile
Everyone, whether crying or smiling,
昨日を I forget
I forget about yesterday.
脱ぎ捨てた
Casting it aside,
自由になる Between
we become free in between.
月明かりに Freak
Freaking out in the moonlight,
誘えば My bro
if you invite me, my bro,
みんな巻き込み急ぐ
involving everyone in a hurry,
Edge of Time
胸に高く
High in my chest,
届く I don't care
reaching out, I don't care,
Make it in the sea
Fun Fun We hit the step step
Keep your doubts to yourself we know we love all
Heat Heat beats like a skip skip
To the paradise Take me please Choo Choo TRAIN
変わりそうもない Scene
A scene that doesn't seem to change
追いかけまわしたい
I want to keep chasing after it
出かけよう この
Let's head out into this
永遠に Say Good-bye
Eternity, say Good-bye
ビルの Upside down oh
Buildings upside down oh
街は All around round
The city is all around round
抜け出して
Breaking free
始めるのさ Good Trip
We're starting a Good Trip
Fun Fun We hit the step step
窓辺からほら We know we love all
Look, from the window, We know we love all
Heat Heat beats like a skip skip
駆け出して 飛び乗る Choo Choo TRAIN
Run out and jump on the Choo Choo TRAIN
Fun Fun We hit the step step
吹き抜ける風 We know we love all
The breeze blowing through, We know we love all
Heat Heat beats like a skip skip
ときめきを運ぶ Choo Choo TRAIN
Carrying the excitement, Choo Choo TRAIN
Fun Fun We hit the step step
窓辺からほら We know we love all
Look, from the window, We know we love all
Heat Heat beats like a skip skip
駆け出して 飛び乗る Choo Choo TRAIN
Run out and jump on the Choo Choo TRAIN
Thanks everyone!
And that was Choo Choo TRAIN with my lovely guests!
But, we still have one more song to go.
ライブもね、残りあと1曲になってしまいました。
We only have one song left in the live performance.
But you guys want an encore, don't you? Of course you do.
まだまだライブ見たいよね？ Of course you do.
You still want to see more of the live, don't you? Of course you do.
After this, I have a members-only encore live,
so I would love it if you'd be able to join that for that as well.
この後もね、メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもやります！
After this, I'll also be doing an encore live limited to membership!
ぜひメンバーシップ入ってね！
Please be sure to join the membership!
So please join the family if you want to watch that! It's gonna be amazing.
And it's gonna have some nice songs. Yes.
歌も歌いますんでね、ぜひ楽しみにしてて下さい。
I'll be singing some songs too, so please look forward to it.
Before we move on to the next song though, I have an extra... EXTRA special announcement!
みんなにスペシャルな、ビッグなお知らせがあります！
I have a special, big announcement for everyone!
I am releasing a new EP! It's been so long!
IRySの新しいEPがリリースされます！すごい久しぶり、もう2年くらい？
A new EP from IRyS will be released! It's been a long time, about 2 years?
It's been like 2 years since my last one.
It's so nice! It's called 'YaBAI'!
IRyS EP 「YaBAI」 YaBA Kawaii Edition
IRyS EP "YaBAI" YaBA Kawaii Edition
タイトルが『YaBAI』になってます。
The title is "YaBAI".
It features 'Carbonated Love' and four new songs.
『Carbonated Love』と、なんと新曲4曲も入ってるEPになっています。
It's an EP that includes "Carbonated Love" and, would you believe it, 4 new songs.
The concept is Eurobeat, if you haven't noticed, and Dance. Yes.
IRyS EP 「YaBAI」 YaBA CHIC Edition
IRyS EP "YaBAI" YaBA CHIC Edition
It's very Euro-y in general, though.
And the digital release will be on July 12th midnight JST,
which will be the 11th in the States. Yes.
コンセプトがユーロ系になっています。
The concept is Euro-style.
もうとってもね、車に合うようなEPになっています。
It's an EP that really suits being in a car.
えーっと、デジタルリリースが7月12日の、えー、0時で、はい！
Um, the digital release is on July 12th at, uh, midnight, yes!
...になります。
...will be.
But this EP will also have a physical release
and pre-orders will begin right after this stream.
えっとね、あの、でもね、デジタルはそうなんですけど、
Well, digital is one thing, but...
えっとフィジカルもなんと出します。
...we're actually doing a physical release too.
えっと、フィジカルのね販売は、
As for the physical sales,
えっと販売開始は、この配信のあとになります。
they will start after this stream.
予約開始か、この配信のあとになります！
Or rather, pre-orders will start after this stream!
There will be two versions of the physical release,
each with a different jacket, each very beautiful.
And a set of two stickers you can use...
I, I yeah, two stickers you can use
to decorate your smartphone or your car.
Yes, you can put it on your car
because one of them is going to be waterproof. Yeah.
えっとね、なんと今回のリリースは、
So, for this release,
えっと2種類のね、あの、ジャケットの種類に
there are two different types of jackets
なっていると思います。えっと、もう両方ともすごい可愛いんで。で、あと、
available. Both of them are really cute. And also,
ステッカーも2種類ずつ出ます。
stickers are coming out in two types each.
なので、多分、あの、全部で4枚、4枚だけど1種類買ったら2枚、
So, probably 4 in total. 2 if you buy one version,
もう1種類買ったら2枚っていう、なんか分かれてる感じになっています。
and 2 if you buy the other. It's split like that.
まあね、ぜひぜひ、あの、スマホや車に貼っていただけると嬉しいな。
Please put them on your smartphone or car.
その2枚のうちの1個はね、あの、
One of those two...
もう、あの、水、防水になってるんで、ぜひ車にも貼ってください。
...is waterproof, so please put it on your car too.
And I will also be hand-signing a limited amount of copies
and shipping them out randomly. Yeah, randomly.
I'll be signing quite a decent amount though,
so you will have a decent chance at getting one. Yay!
Gacha! Everyone's favorite, my favorite Gacha.
Yes.
えっとね、直筆サインも、あの限定な数、
Also, a limited number of hand-signed copies...
直筆サインも、あの、やりますんですけど、あの、なんと、
I'll be doing those, and it's actually...
そのランダム配布になっております。
...a random distribution.
なので、あの、買ったら直筆が当たってるかどうか楽しみだね！
So look forward to seeing if you get a signed one when you buy it!
もし、可能性をその直筆が当たる可能性を上げたかったら、
If you want to increase your chances of getting a signature,
ね、何枚か、ね、買っていただけると嬉しいな。
I'd be happy if you bought a few.
あの、でもね、結構な数を、あのサインしたんで、
But I signed quite a lot,
まあ、そこそこのいい確率で当たるかと思います。
so I think you have a pretty good chance of winning.
Anyways, I'm really excited to show you
the new songs I've been working on.
Do you want to listen to one of them?
Do you really want to listen to one of them?
Are you begging right now?
You have to be begging on your knees right now,
just like for the encore stuff, you know, the usual.
しゃーないなあ！
Guess I have no choice!
The last song will be a new song from the EP
with a very, very special guest.
もう楽しみだし緊張する。
I'm excited and nervous.
なんと、最後の曲はね、このEPに収録されている新曲を
For the last song, I'll be singing a new song from this EP
特別ゲストと一緒に歌います！
with a special guest!
とってもね、ホットな新曲になっています。
It's a very hot new song.
もう本当にこのEPにふさわしい素晴らしい1曲になっています。
It's a wonderful song that's truly fitting for this EP.
It's gonna be a really hot, nice IRyS song,
if you haven't, you know, realized that yet.
And I can't wait for you guys to play it in the car.
みんな車の中でぜひ流してくださいね！
Everyone, please play it in your car!
では、Please listen to my new original:
Now, please listen to my new original:
DIAMOND GIRLFRIEND!
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Save me, I think I'm freezing up,
so cold inside
舞台はquiet room 二たり
The stage is a quiet room for two
Save me, I need a guiding touch
in these dark times
恋人たちのシーン
A scene for lovers
Inside the maze of your heart,
I'm the soul that strays
That's why
But baby look at me, you're not blind,
Oh, can't you see that I can be refined
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time
To be your DIAMOND GIRLFRIEND
Overheating love machine, burning hot!
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
So precious girlfriend go go go
Overheating love machine, burning hot!
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
On the
Nothing stops this awakened soul
break it all break it all break it all
The Diamond Girlfriend
しなやかなキャラ豹変
A sleek character's sudden transformation
ビートまとい まき散らすのは プリンプリンのSparkleだ
Wearing the beat, scattering bouncy Sparkles
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword バッチリ
Just heat it and wheel it, make the sword perfect
まぶしすぎて目が眩むGem
A Gem so bright it blinds your eyes
Trust me, your weary eyes betray what you've tried to hide
まぶしさで目が眩むGem
A dazzling Gem that blinds you
言葉無しで伝われ
Let it reach you without words
Trust me, I'll never shy away from your dark side
空気が変わるフェイズ
The phase where the atmosphere changes
Under the pressure and fire, see these ashes reborn
Your rebirth
強くなれ
Be strong
Let me show you who I really am,
Oh yeah...
In the name of love, I'll be a gem Ah
Your heart is super hot right now, it's time
I'll be your DIAMOND GIRLFRIEND
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
So precious girlfriend go go go
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot! hot!
Into the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all
break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
Now "C" is your atomic symbol
ぐるぐる回せ真っ赤っ赤になるまでWimble
Spin it round and round until it's bright red, Wimble
愛が足りないとか闇が深いほど
The more love is lacking or the deeper the darkness
勝ち誇るGemあつかう
Handling the gem that triumphs
I'm a jeweler さあ踊りなさい
I'm a jeweler, now dance
Shine on, shine bright, light my flame
until it all melts away... Eh eh
until it all melts away... Its away...
Ready?
Are you ready?
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot!
Untouchable
Silver flames consuming me, let them light the way
So precious girlfriend go go go
Overheating love machine, burning hot! hot! hot! hot!
On the rock machine
Nothing stops this awakened soul, break it all
break it all, break it all, break it all
No one can dull my shine tonight
No one can dull my shine
Thank you so much for watching my live!
The CD for my new EP, YaBA!, will be open
for pre-orders after this.
It includes the new song DIAMOND GIRLFRIEND
that I just performed featuring MOTSU-san.
There are two versions that will be available
for purchase, the YaBA KAWAII edition
and the YaBA CHIC edition.
The YaBA KAWAII jacket illustration is drawn
by maesjuw-san,
and the YaBA CHIC jacket illustration is drawn
by SYAGAMU-san.
The jackets are reversible, so you will be able to
switch between the two no matter which version you buy.
Both jackets are absolutely adorable!
The main difference between the two versions
are the sticker set designs that will be included.
Both sets are drawn by LIEN-sensei.
There are two different types of stickers
included with each EP version.
One of which is a larger size and waterproof, so
it would be great if you could put it on your car.
The other is a smartphone size, so you can take
it with you wherever you go.
Also, the alternate jacket may have a
handwritten signature on it, so please look forward to it!
This EP is packed with Euro sounds,
I'm really looking forward to sharing them all
with you and I hope you buy a copy.
Stay tuned after the credits for the DIAMOND
GIRLFRIEND MV premiere,
and I'll see you guys in the members only part 2!
Woo!
Thank you so much for watching &
celebrating my Birthday with me!
I put all my heart into this live &
I hope that you can continue
to support me in my singing journey
as we reach for the stars
TOGETHER! I love you guys!
いつも ありがとう☆!
Thank you as always☆!